# Jakub Tordoff

# **Full Stack Web Engineer**

kubator21@protonmail.com https://jakubtordoff.com 414.210.7806

## Overview

I am an experienced software developer, well versed in many platforms and tools, delivering high quality software and features. I am comfortable discussing requirements and engaging in heads-down coding during the sprint to deliver them. A lively debater and a passionate collaborator, I understand that the team succeeds together. I enjoy tackling hard problems and designing solutions with the big picture in mind. I love experimenting with new frameworks, learning new patterns and automating the tedious tasks. I have a talent for leading technical projects and driving initiatives. My curiosity fuels my hunger to continuously learn and improve my skill set.

## **Experience**

### American Family Insurance/ Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

October 2020 - PRESENT, Madison, WI

- Designed, collaborated and successfully migrated several applications to AWS.
- Effectively developed Angular components using NGRX, RXJS and best practices to deliver many business features.
- Eagerly learned new technologies on the fly such as NestJS, React, AWS services, development patterns, performance optimizations and anything that is needed
- Organized, designed and developed highly efficient CICD processes that include security scans, testing, and deployment to many environments
- Maintained a monorepo that included SPAs and APIs hosted on AWS.
  Actively stayed on top of the latest frameworks, releases and new patterns supporting industries best practices.
- Supported and resolved production incidents for applications that were utilized by millions of users.
- Reviewed, improved, and implemented complex reactive user interfaces.

#### Northwestern Mutual / Test Engineering Manager

July 2020 - October 2020, Milwaukee, WI

- Managed a group of 10 people across five feature teams.
- Improved development and testing processes to shorten the turnaround time for new features.
- Successfully achieved company goals and propelled testing maturity.
- Got directly involved with projects to support testing practices and advocated for high quality coding and testing standards.

#### Northwestern Mutual / Lead SDET

August 2016 - June 2020, Milwaukee, WI

- Leader of redesigning and utilizing modern test automation tools built upon Node, JavaScript and git.
- Streamlined many testing efforts to deliver results quickly which carved times for exploratory testing that found meaningful bugs before deployment.
- Developed and maintained testing frameworks that supported applications with thousands of users.

- Enforced best coding practice by reviewing merge requests with constructive feedback.
- Built many automation tools/frameworks from the ground up to meet specific needs.

### **Education**

# **University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee** / B.S. in Information Science and Technology

August 2016, Milwaukee

Undergraduate Coursework: Senior Capstone Website; Databases; Programming Languages; Networking, iOS and Android App development.

## **Projects**

Personal Resume Website <a href="https://jakubtordoff.com">https://jakubtordoff.com</a>

Mock Amazon Website (2020)

https://gitlab.com/ktordoff13/amazon-clone

Messenger Real Time Chat

https://gitlab.com/ktordoff13/facebook-messenger-clone

# **Technologies**

JavaScript, Bash, Git, CICD, HTML, CSS, React, Angular, yml, TypeScript, NestJS, AWS, Jira, Confluence, Node, GitLab, VS Code, wordpress, Postman, Jest, NX, Nrwl, Cypress, BrowserStack, SauceLabs, postgresql,